# **Andy Brummitt**

## Web Developer

21 Homefield Drive Braintree CM7 2DF 07562 010888 andybrummitt93@gmail.com

Portfolio: <a href="https://andy-brummitt.co.uk/">https://andy-brummitt.co.uk/</a>
Github: <a href="https://github.com/Andybrummitt">https://github.com/Andybrummitt</a>

**LinkedIn:** <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/andy-brumm">https://www.linkedin.com/in/andy-brumm</a> itt-dev/

## **SKILLS**

Javascript | React | CSS | SCSS | HTML | Node | Express | Firebase | Git

## **WEB DEVELOPMENT**

I have two years experience in creating websites and have a strong knowledge of front-end development with React and Javascript.

My portfolio is the best representation of my work.

Portfolio Link: <a href="https://andy-brummitt.co.uk/">https://andy-brummitt.co.uk/</a>

## **Some Personal Projects**

Mixin <a href="http://mixinapp.herokuapp.com/">http://mixinapp.herokuapp.com/</a>

Mixin is a cocktail information web app that utilises the cocktailDB REST API to offer the user a seamless experience searching for cocktails that they can make.

Tag My Tunes <a href="https://tagmytunes.herokuapp.com/">https://tagmytunes.herokuapp.com/</a>

My most recent project is a website that receives .mp3 files from the user and returns a .zip file of the songs with the artist and title fields (ID3 tags) populated correctly (to the best of the algorithm's ability). When converting music from videos with popular converting websites, the ID3 tags are often not

populated at all. This project aids the user in automation of the tedious task of manual editing the tags themselves.

Battleship Game <a href="https://battleshipjsgame.herokuapp.com/">https://battleshipjsgame.herokuapp.com/</a>

This project is essentially a web based version of the popular board game, Battleship, with a graphical user interface. Users can battle against a bot that has been programmed to guess random tiles until it hits a ship tile, in which case it will guess tiles around the ship tile.

### **Summary**

Despite not having any formal experience yet, I believe I have the passion and discipline to make it in this industry, having built apps and sites from my own intuition for the past two years. I am fully dedicated to this career and I feel that's reflective of my portfolio.

## **EDUCATION**

Writtle University College - BSc Hons: Sports & Exercise Performance 2014 - 2017 Grade: 2:2 (59%)

**Chelmsford College - Diploma Media Studies** 

2009 - 2011 Grade: Merit

## **EXPERIENCE**

**Order Fulfilment, Customer Support** - Xylem Holdings (table-tennis-tables.co.uk)

May 2013 - PRESENT

Working in a relatively small company, I have had many roles during my time here. I started out picking and packing orders and handling dispatch but soon moved on to manage a small group of employees in the department.

As I was interested in web development, I am often asked to consult with my employer to make small changes on the e-commerce website using my HTML and CSS knowledge.

Throughout my time I have regularly provided customer support which has given me lots of experience in dealing with a range of customer service inquiries.

## **Professional Ice Hockey Player** - Hull Stingrays

August 2011 - December 2012

After completing college I signed a professional contract with Hull Stingrays, an Elite League team. This was a dream of mine growing up, having played since the age of four. I played for the team until December 2012 when I was injured playing for Great Britain in the World Junior Championships in Ukraine. During this time I learned to remain disciplined and focused during times of struggle and reinforced my teamwork skills learned earlier in a professional environment.